Cable Hogue says … “Do unto others … as you would have others do unto you.”
The Ballad of Cable Hogue is a comedy, western,
action film directed by Sam Peckinpah.
Double-crossed and left without water in the desert,
Cable Hogue is saved when he finds a spring.
It is in just the right spot for a much needed rest stop on the local
stagecoach line, and Hogue uses this to his advantage.
He builds a house and makes money off the stagecoach passengers.
Hildy, a prostitute from the nearest town, moves in with him.
Hogue has everything going his way until the advent of the
automobile ends the era of the stagecoach.
Cable Hogue, played by Jason Robards.
Hildy, played by Stella Stevens.
Ben Fairchild, played by Slim Pickens.
Joshua, played by David Warner.
Taggart, played by L.Q. Jones.
Bowen, played by Strother Martin.
The Ballad of Cable Hogue is a 1970 American Technicolor Western comedy film directed by
Sam Peckinpah and starring Jason Robards, Stella Stevens and David Warner.
Set in the Arizona desert during a period when the frontier was closing, the
film follows three years in the life of a failed prospector.
While unmistakably a Western, the movie is
unconventional for the genre and for the director.
It contains only a few brief scenes of violence and gunplay, relying more on a subtly
crafted story that could better be characterized as comedic in nature.
The film explores themes of prostitute, homeless
person, desert, stagecoach, prospector.
The tone is lighthearted.